A Guide to the Harold P. Fabian papers FA071
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc., 1940-1981; 3; 10.8 Cubic Feet 28 document cases
  - Budget and Accounting, 1941-1953 (Box 37, Folder 396)
  - Budget and Accounting - Time Book, 1942, 1947 (Box 37, Folder 397)
  - Continental National Bank - Regular Account, 1949-1956 (Box 38, Folder 398)
  - Continental National Bank - Special Account, 1948-1952 (Box 38, Folder 399)
  - Harold P. Fabian - Agent, 1942-1945, 1952 (Box 38, Folder 400)
  - Harold P. Fabian - Agent - Winger Reports, 1942-1944 (Box 38, Folder 401)
  - Continental National Bank - Harold P. Fabian - Agent Account, 1950-1952 (Box 38, Folder 402)
  - Continental National Bank - Harold P. Fabian - Agent Account, 1950-1952 (Box 38, Folder 403)
  - Continental National Bank - Harold P. Fabian - Agent Account, 1952-1954 (Box 39, Folder 404)
  - Richard Winger Budget, 1944 (Box 39, Folder 405)
  - Property Taxes - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Lodge Companies and Ranches, 1949-1950 (Box 39, Folder 406)
  - State of Utah - Tax Form TC-55, 1946 (Box 39, Folder 407)
  - U. S. Treasury Department - IRS Form 990, 1946-1950 (Box 39, Folder 408)
  - Insurance, 1942-1945, 1950, 1952 (Box 39, Folder 409)
  - Insurance Survey, 1944 (Box 39, Folder 410)
  - Report of Self-Insurance Plan, 1955-1956 (Box 39, Folder 411)
  - Employees' Retirement Trust, 1956-1961 (Box 39, Folder 412)
  - Corporate Correspondence, 1942-1948 (Box 40, Folder 413)
  - Corporate Correspondence, 1942-1948 (Box 40, Folder 414)
  - Corporate Correspondence, 1942-1948 (Box 40, Folder 415)
  - Corporate Correspondence, 1942-1948 (Box 40, Folder 416)
  - Corporate Correspondence, 1942-1948 (Box 40, Folder 417)
  - Corporate Correspondence, 1949-1971 (Box 41, Folder 418)
  - Corporate Correspondence, 1949-1971 (Box 41, Folder 419)
  - Corporate Correspondence, 1949-1971 (Box 41, Folder 420)
  - Corporate Correspondence, 1949-1971 (Box 41, Folder 421)
  - Corporate Correspondence, 1949-1971 (Box 41, Folder 422)
  - Superintendent of Properties, 1947-February 1948 (Box 41, Folder 423)
  - Superintendent of Properties, 1947-February 1948 (Box 41, Folder 424)
  - Superintendent of Properties, March-June 1948, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 425)
  - Correspondence - Horace M. Albright, 1943-1976 (Box 42, Folder 426)
  - Correspondence - Horace M. Albright, 1943-1976 (Box 42, Folder 427)
  - Correspondence - Horace M. Albright, 1943-1976 (Box 42, Folder 428)
  - Correspondence - Horace M. Albright, 1943-1976 (Box 42, Folder 429)
  - Correspondence - Kenneth Chorley, 1943-1956 (Box 43, Folder 430)
  - Correspondence - Kenneth Chorley, 1943-1956 (Box 43, Folder 431)
  - Correspondence - Kenneth Chorley, 1943-1956 (Box 43, Folder 432)
  - Correspondence - Kenneth Chorley, 1943-1956 (Box 43, Folder 433)
  - Correspondence - Kenneth Chorley, 1943-1956 (Box 43, Folder 434)
  - Correspondence - Chandler Cudlipp, 1946-1954 (Box 44, Folder 435)
  - Correspondence - Nancy Hanks, 1959-1979 (Box 44, Folder 436)
  - Correspondence - Lester Hunt, 1945-1946 (Box 44, Folder 437)
  - Correspondence - A. E. Kendrew, 1942-1945 (Box 44, Folder 438)
  - Correspondence - "Comments on Plans for the Development of Teton National Park," by A. E. Kendrew, 1942 (Box 44, Folder 439)
  - Correspondence - Leslie Miller, 1945-1946 (Box 44, Folder 440)
  - Correspondence - Fairfield Osborn, 1945-1946 (Box 44, Folder 441)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1943-1974 (Box 44, Folder 442)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1975-1981 (Box 45, Folder 443)
  - Correspondence - John D. Rockefeller 3rd and John D. Rockefeller IV, 1976-1978 (Box 45, Folder 444)
  - Correspondence - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1945-1979 (Box 45, Folder 445)
  - Correspondence - Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1963-1979 (Box 45, Folder 446)
  - Correspondence - Vanderbilt Webb, 1945-1954 (Box 45, Folder 447)
  - Correspondence - Richard Winger, 1943-1946, 1966 (Box 45, Folder 448)
  - Correspondence - Richard Winger, 1943-1946, 1966 (Box 45, Folder 449)
  - Jackson Hole National Monument, 1943-1945 (Box 46, Folder 450)
  - Jackson Hole National Monument, 1943-1945 (Box 46, Folder 451)
  - Jackson Hole National Monument, 1943-1945 (Box 46, Folder 452)
  - Jackson Hole National Monument, 1943-1945 (Box 46, Folder 453)
  - Jackson Hole National Monument - National Park Service, 1942-1945 (Box 46, Folder 454)
  - Jackson Hole National Monument - "The Controversy" by Leslie A. Miller, ca. 1943 (Box 46, Folder 455)
  - Jackson Hole National Monument - House Resolution 2241 (Box 46, Folder 456)
    Hearings, 1943 Veto, 1945
  - Jackson Hole National Monument - House Resolution 1330 (Box 47, Folder 457)
    Hearings, 1947 Report, n.d.
  - "Report on Jackson Hole Project" by Harold P. Fabian, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 458)
  - Master Plan for Grand Teton National Park and Jackson Hole National Monument, 1947 (Box 47, Folder 459)
  - Jackson Hole National Monument - Historical View, 1948 (Box 47, Folder 460)
  - Jackson Hole National Monument - Washington Conference, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 461)
  - Jackson Hole National Monument - Washington Conference - National Park Service (NPS) Map, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 462)
  - Map of Private Property Inside Grand Teton National Park, 1951 (Box 47, Folder 463)
  - Maps of Grand Teton National Park Master Plan, 1957 (Box 47, Folder 464)
  - Seminar Paper on Yellowstone and Grand Teton Controversy, ca. 1961 (Box 47, Folder 465)
  - Memorial Tablet to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1952-1953, 1955, 1969 (Box 47, Folder 466)
  - Memorial Tablet to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1953 (Box 47, Folder 467)
    Ink Drawing of Tablet, Site Plan.
  - "A Study of the Resources, People and Economy of Teton County, Wyoming", 1959 (Box 47, Folder 468)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Moose Development, 1946-1947 (Box 48, Folder 469)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Correspondence, 1944-1958, 1964, 1974 (Box 48, Folder 470)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Correspondence, 1944-1958, 1964, 1974 (Box 48, Folder 471)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Correspondence, 1944-1958, 1964, 1974 (Box 48, Folder 472)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Correspondence, 1944-1958, 1964, 1974 (Box 48, Folder 473)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Dedication, August 20, 1949 (Box 49, Folder 474)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - List of Photographs of Ferry Restoration, 1949 (Box 49, Folder 475)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - A. E. Kendrew's Blueprints of Buildings and Plot, 1942 (Box 49, Folder 476)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - A. E. Kendrew's Blueprint of Apparatus, 1942 (Box 49, Folder 477)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Plat Map of Menor Homestead, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 478)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Plans and Construction, 1949-1950 (Box 49, Folder 479)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Geneva Steel Company Blueprint of Apparatus, 1949 (Box 49, Folder 480)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Wilking Blueprints of Ferry and Apparatus, 1949 (Box 49, Folder 481)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Financial Reports, 1949-1952 (Box 49, Folder 482)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - "Jackson Hole: How to Discover and Enjoy It," by Josephine Fabian, 1949 (Box 49, Folder 483)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Notes of Interview with Cal Carrington, 1956 (Box 49, Folder 484)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Pamphlets, 1952, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 485)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Ferry Ranch Inn, 1950 (Box 49, Folder 486)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Ferry Ranch Inn Inventories, 1951-1952 (Box 50, Folder 487)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Historic Structures Report on Maud Noble's Cabin, 1970 (Box 50, Folder 488)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Notes, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 489)
  - Menor's Ferry Restoration - Newspaper Articles, 1949-1977 (Box 50, Folder 490)
  - Wildlife Park - Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 50, Folder 491)
  - Wildlife Park - Lease, 1946, 1948 (Box 50, Folder 492)
  - Wildlife Park - Financial Statements, 1947-1948 (Box 50, Folder 493)
  - Wildlife Park - Research and Publicity, 1945-1946 (Box 50, Folder 494)
  - Colter Bay Development, 1955 (Box 51, Folder 495)
  - Mt. Rainier Study, 1959 (Box 52, Folder 496)
  - Sublette County Historical Society, Inc., 1965-1968 (Box 52, Folder 497)
  - Old South Pass Historical Preserve, 1967-1968 (Box 52, Folder 498)
  - "The Wyoming Press", 1902 (Box 52, Folder 499)
  - Magazine Articles and Pamphlets - Wyoming and Jackson Hole (Box 52, Folder 500)
  - Transcript of Oral History by Harold P. Fabian, 1966 (Box 53, Folder 501)
  - Water Rights, 1942-1951 (Box 53, Folder 502)
  - Leases and Permits, 1942-1945 (Box 53, Folder 503)
  - Withdrawal Orders with Map, 1945-1946 (Box 53, Folder 504)
  - Acreage, 1949, 1951 (Box 53, Folder 505)
  - Vehicle Records, 1947-1952 (Box 53, Folder 506)
  - Inventory and Recommendations for Lodges, 1951 (Box 53, Folder 507)
  - Elbo Ranch (Box 53, Folder 508)
    Correspondence and Inventory, 1948 Site Plan, c. 1948
    See also Boxes 7 and 13.
  - Transfer to U. S. - JHP A-C, 1945, 1949-1952 (Box 54, Folder 509)
    See also Boxes 57 and 60.
  - Personnel - JHP5, 1947-1951 (Box 54, Folder 510)
  - Research and Publicity - JHP6, 1943, 1945-1949, 1969, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 511)
    See also Box 57.
  - Arthur H. Carhart Correspondence - JHP6, 1943-1947 (Box 54, Folder 512)
  - Arthur H. Carhart Correspondence - JHP6, 1943-1947 (Box 54, Folder 513)
  - Arthur H. Carhart Correspondence - JHP6, 1948-1949 (Box 55, Folder 514)
  - Arthur H. Carhart Correspondence - JHP6, 1948-1949 (Box 55, Folder 515)
  - Arthur H. Carhart Program Releases - JHP6, 1947-1949 (Box 55, Folder 516)
  - Arthur H. Carhart Program Releases - JHP6, 1947-1949 (Box 55, Folder 517)
  - Bar BC Ranch - JHP10, 1940-1944, 1947, 1949 (Box 55, Folder 518)
  - Elk Ranch - JHP13, 1946-1948, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 519)
  - Elk Ranch - JHP13, 1946-1948, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 520)
  - Winter Sports - JHP16, 1946-1947 (Box 56, Folder 521)
  - East Side Road - JHP17, 1946-1948 (Box 56, Folder 522)
  - Secondary Road (Kelly) - JHP17a, 1949 (Box 56, Folder 523)
  - Moseley/Reed Hay Contract - JHP19, 1940-1947 (Box 56, Folder 524)
    See also Box 58.
  - Izaak Walton League Correspondence - JHP27, 1945-1950 (Box 56, Folder 525)
  - Izaak Walton League Publicity - JHP27, 1945, 1947, 1948-1950 (Box 56, Folder 526)
  - Jackson Hole National Monument Articles - JHP28, 1947-1948, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 527)
  - Economic Report on Jackson Hole Area, by Leslie Miller - JHP29, 1947-1947 (Box 57, Folder 528)
  - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (Box 57, Folder 529)
    Certificate of Incorporation, 1940 By-Laws Certificate of Agent of Foreign Corp., 1947, 1949, 1952 Certificate of Existence, 1952 Utah Charter, 1946 Utah Decree of Withdrawal, 1953
  - Deed Conveying Land to U. S., 1949 (Box 57, Folder 530)
  - Corporate Forms (Box 57, Folder 531)
  - Annual Reports to Secretary of State of Wyoming, 1940-1947, 1950-1951, 1954 (Box 57, Folder 532)
  - Harold P. Fabian - Agent - Statement of Receipts and Disbursements, 1943-1944 (Box 57, Folder 533)
  - Board of Equalization - Tax Reassessment, 1950 (Box 57, Folder 534)
  - Jackson Hole National Monument - Proclamation Establishing Monument (with Maps), 1943 (Box 57, Folder 535)
  - Jackson Hole National Monument - Senate Lands Committee Hearings - Posters, 1943 (Box 57, Folder 536)
  - Jackson Hole National Monument - House Resolution 2241, 1944 (Box 57, Folder 537)
  - Water Rights, 1947-1951 (Box 57, Folder 538)
  - Transfer to U. S. - JHP4A-C, 1949-1952 (Box 57, Folder 539)
    See also Boxes 54 and 60.
  - Research and Publicity - JHP6, 1947-1949 (Box 57, Folder 540)
    See also Box 54.
  - Moseley/Reed Hay Contract - JHP19, 1940-1947 (Box 57, Folder 541)
    See also Box 56.
  - Land Acquisition - Abercrombie - 2-41-116, 1946-1949 (Box 58, Folder 542)
  - Land Acquisition - Lester I. May - -42-116, 1950 (Box 58, Folder 543)
  - Leases (Box 58, Folder 544)
    Carmichael, 1948-1949 Chambers, 1947-1948 Driscoll and Wiley, 1948
  - Leases (Box 58, Folder 545)
    Erwin, 1947-1948 Gillette (Service Station at Moose), 1947
  - Leases (Box 58, Folder 546)
    Gordon, 1946-1948 Hardeman, 1947-1948 Hunter, 1949 Irwin, 1947-1948
  - Leases (Box 58, Folder 547)
    James, 1947-1948 Lange, 1948-1949
  - Leases (Box 58, Folder 548)
    H. May, 1947, 1949 J. May, 1947 Moulton, 1947-1948 Porter, 1947-1948
  - Leases (Box 58, Folder 549)
    Reed (Moseley Land and Cattle Company, Elk Ranch), 1941-1942, 1944-1945 Robertson (Elbo Ranch), 1948
  - Leases (Box 58, Folder 550)
    Seebohm, 1947 Tarbell, 1947-1948 Timberline Ldt. (Elbo Ranch), 1948 Turner, 1946-1949
  - Leases (Box 58, Folder 551)
    Wells, 1947-1948 Wesley, 1943, 1945 L. Wilson, 1948 W. Wilson, 1947-1949, Wolff, 1949 Worthington, 1947-1949
  - Real Estate Activities (RE) 1 - Current, 1946-1949 (Box 58, Folder 552)
  - Real Estate Activities (RE) 2 - Oil and Gas Leases, 1945-1948 (Box 58, Folder 553)
  - Real Estate Activities (RE) 2 - Oil and Gas Leases (Maps), 1945-1948 (Box 59, Folder 554)
  - Real Estate Activities (Box 59, Folder 555)
    Real Estate Activities (RE) 4 - Barker, 1947-1948 Real Estate Activities (RE) 6 - Carmichael House, 1948
  - Real Estate Activities (Box 59, Folder 556)
    Real Estate Activities (RE) 7 - Chambers, 1947 Real Estate Activities (RE) 8 - Christensen, 1946-1948
  - Real Estate Activities (Box 59, Folder 557)
    Real Estate Activities (RE) 9 - Dornan, 1947-1951 Real Estate Activities (RE) 11 - Geck, 1946-1947, 1949
  - Real Estate Activities (Box 59, Folder 558)
    Real Estate Activities (RE) 12 - Goutard, 1948 Real Estate Activities (RE) 13 - Laura Sherman Gray, 1949-1950
  - Real Estate Activities (RE) 13a - John C. Simpson (Employment), 1942-1943 (Box 59, Folder 559)
  - Real Estate Activities (RE) 14 - Huff, 1946-1949 (Box 59, Folder 560)
  - Real Estate Activities (RE) 15 - Effie Jean Johnson, 1947-1949 (Box 59, Folder 561)
  - Real Estate Activities (RE) 16 - Kimmel Purchase from Jackson Hole Preserve (JHP), Inc., 1946-1947 (Box 59, Folder 562)
  - Real Estate Activities (RE) 17 - Lucas, 1946-1949 (Box 59, Folder 563)
  - Real Estate Activities (Box 60, Folder 564)
    Real Estate Activites (RE) 17a - Gottfreid Feuz, 1948-1951 Real Estate Activites (RE) 17b - Ida B. Chambers, 1950-1951
  - Real Estate Activities (Box 60, Folder 565)
    Real Estate Activites (RE) 19 - Laura B. Seebohm, 1948-1949 Real Estate Activites (RE) 21 - White Grass, 1948-1950
  - Real Estate Activities (RE) 22 - Wendell Wilson, 1949 (Box 60, Folder 566)
  - Real Estate Activities (Box 60, Folder 567)
    Real Estate Activites (RE) 23 - Ramshorn Ranch, 1949 Real Estate Activites (RE) 24 - Lewis (Coulter Huyler), 1949
  - Real Estate Activities (RE) 25 - Gabbey Purchase, 1949-1952 (Box 60, Folder 568)
  - Real Estate Activities (RE) 26 - The Highlands, 1950-1951 (Box 60, Folder 569)
  - Real Estate Activities (RE) 28 (P152) - Transfer to U. S., 1945, 1947, 1949 (Box 60, Folder 570)
    See also Boxes 54 and 57.
  - Real Estate Activity - 1950 Purchases (Box 60, Folder 571)
  - Real Estate Activity - Huyler (Bear Paw Ranch), 1941, 1943-1952 (Box 60, Folder 572)
  - Real Estate Activity - Huyler (Bear Paw Ranch), 1941, 1943-1952 (Box 60, Folder 573)
  - Real Estate Activity - Huyler (Bear Paw Ranch) - Legal Documents, 1943-1949 (Box 61, Folder 574)
  - Real Estate Activity - Spears (R Lazy S Ranch), 1947-1948, 1953-1954 (Box 61, Folder 575)
- JY Ranch, 1927-1958; 4; 1.2 Cubic Feet 4 document cases
  This series contains correspondence, financial statements, and property management files. The correspondence relates to the purchase of the Ranch and its operation. Legal-size documents are grouped in Box 65.
  - Correspondence, 1927-1943 (Box 62, Folder 576)
  - Correspondence, 1927-1943 (Box 62, Folder 577)
  - Correspondence, 1927-1943 (Box 62, Folder 578)
  - Correspondence, 1927-1943 (Box 62, Folder 579)
  - Correspondence, 1927-1943 (Box 62, Folder 580)
  - Correspondence, 1946, 1948-1954 (Box 63, Folder 581)
  - Property Correspondence - 36-42-116, 1935-1958 (Box 63, Folder 582)
  - Property Correspondence - Lucas, Fleming, Hobbs, 1939-1943 (Box 63, Folder 583)
  - Federal Land Bank Loan, 1931-1938 (Box 63, Folder 584)
  - Financial Reports, 1939, 1951 (Box 63, Folder 585)
  - Budget and Accounting, 1940, 1945-1949 (Box 63, Folder 586)
  - Budget and Accounting, 1940, 1945-1949 (Box 63, Folder 587)
  - Budget and Accounting, 1950-1955 (Box 64, Folder 588)
  - Budget and Accounting, 1950-1955 (Box 64, Folder 589)
  - Receipts, 1934, 1940-1941, 1943 (Box 64, Folder 590)
  - Brand Certificates, 1926, 1932, 1935 (Box 64, Folder 591)
  - Lower JY Restoration, 1946-1948 (Box 64, Folder 592)
  - Trail Guide, 1949 (Box 64, Folder 593)
  - History of the JY, 1975 (Box 64, Folder 594)
  - Property Purchase - Legal Documents - Lucas, Fleming, Hobbs, 1939-1940 (Box 65, Folder 595)
  - Property Purchase - Legal Documents - Lucas, Fleming, Hobbs, 1939-1940 (Box 65, Folder 596)
  - Property Purchase - Legal Documents - Lucas, Fleming, Hobbs, 1939-1940 (Box 65, Folder 597)
  - JY Ranch (Box 65, Folder 598)
    Inventory, 1932 Appraisal, 1938 Bill of Sale (Personal Items) to JHP, Inc., 1947
  - Federal Land Bank Loan, 1931-1938 (Box 65, Folder 599)
  - Leases for 16-42-116, 1928-1948 (Box 65, Folder 600)
  - Lower Valley Power and Light, 1954 (Box 65, Folder 601)
- Caneel Bay Plantation, Inc., 1955-1965; 5; 0.5 Cubic Feet 1 document case
  This series consists of minutes, correspondence, and financial reports.
  - Report on Establishing St. John Island as a National Park, 1939 (Box 66, Folder 602)
    Map, 1955.
  - Board of Directors Minutes, 1956, 1960, 1962-1965 (Box 66, Folder 603)
  - Correspondence, 1955-1956, 1964 (Box 66, Folder 604)
  - Financial Reports, 1960-1962 (Box 66, Folder 605)
  - Budget and Accounting, 1956-1957, 1961-1962, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 606)
  - Pamphlets (Box 66, Folder 607)
  - Magazine Articles, 1955-1956 (Box 66, Folder 608)
  - Mauna Kea Beach Hotel (Box 66, Folder 609)
- Conservation, 1961-1975; 6; 0.5 Cubic Feet 1 document case
  This series consists of minutes and reports from the American Conservation Association, Inc. and the Citizens' Advisory Committee on Environmental Quality.
  - American Conservation Association, Inc. - Annual Meetings, 1961-1962, 1968, 1970, 1974-1975 (Box 67, Folder 610)
  - American Conservation Association, Inc. - Annual Report, 1969 (Box 67, Folder 611)
  - White House Conference on Natural Beauty, May 24-25, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 612)
  - Citizens' Advisory Committee on Environmental Quality and Citizen's Advisory Committee on Recreation and Natural Beauty, 1967-1968, 1974 (Box 67, Folder 613)
  - Citizens' Advisory Committee on Environmental Quality - Agenda for August 31, 1970 Meeting (Box 67, Folder 614)
  - Citizens' Advisory Committee on Environmental Quality - Publications (Box 67, Folder 615)
    "Community Action for Environmental Quality," 1970 Annual Report, 1972
- Non-Textual Material, 7
  This series contains slides, miscellaneous items, and audio tapes. There are 177 slides, the majority of which were taken on Fabian's vacation trips to the Caribbean between 1960 and 1964. There are also images from Menor's Ferry and the Ferry Ranch. The 36 audio tapes were produced by Fabian between 1949 and 1973. The tapes have not been reviewed for specific content; the titles used here were assigned by Fabian.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
  Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
  Conditions Governing Access
  RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
  - Audiovisual materials, 1
    Arrangement
    Arranged by accession.
    Scope and Contents
    A group of eighteen home movies/travelogues from Harold P. Fabian. Shots of Yellowstone National Park, Jackson Hole, Cascade Canyon, Moose Church, and a rodeo.
    When requesting to view films -- please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1902).
    If the item does not have a designated AV number, please refer to the Title and the Film Number (which consists of a combination of Roman numerals and alphanumerics - example: III 14.1-6).
    - Yellowstone, 1938 (Reel AV 1326)
      Conditions Governing Access note
      All inquires to view films require advanced notice of at least 24 hours, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those not available in modern formats, may be restricted from scholarly access at the discretion of RAC.
      Train arriving at Yellowstone; Morning Glory pool; geysers erupting; Kesler Cascade; black bear in forest; children playing
      File Plan
      IV 3A7 Fa 1
    - Wilson Rodeo, 1942 (Reel AV 1327)
      Horseback riding with family; footage of rodeo
      IV 3A7 Fa 10
    - Summer 1939 (Reel AV 1328)
      Picnic with family; visiting the farm
      IV 3A7 Fa 11
    - East 1940 (Reel AV 1329)
      Fishing; crowds on street in formal attired; boarding United Airlines Mainliner; shots from air flying to Chicago.
      IV 3A7 Fa 12
    - New York October 1938, 1938 October (Reel AV 1330)
      Driving through Jackson Hole; Caribou National Forest; some very dark footage of cars.
      IV 3A7 Fa 13
    - Jackson Hole, July 1938, 1938 July (Reel AV 1331)
      Log cabins; views of mountains; visiting Elk Ranch
      IV 3A7 Fa 14
    - Summer 1942, 1942 Summer (Reel AV 1332)
      Farm equipment; boat ride on lake; mountain views; horseback riding.
      IV 3A7 Fa 15
    - Jackson Hole, 1938 (Reel AV 1333)
      JY Ranch; horseback riding; making hay bales at farm
      IV 3A7 Fa 16
    - Boat Trip 1940 (Reel AV 1334)
      Boat ride; horseback riding with family
      IV 3A7 Fa 17
    - Fabian, 1940 (Reel AV 1335)
      Cascade Canyon: mountain views; fishing; horseback riding with family
      IV 3A7 Fa 18
    - Game in Yellowstone, 1939 (Reel AV 1336)
      Views of mountains and water; deer in forest
      IV 3A7 Fa 2
    - Moose Church, 1938 (Reel AV 1337)
      Chapel of the Transfiguration in Jackson Hole, Wyoming; horseback riding with family; views of mountains
      IV 3A7 Fa 3
    - June 1940, 1940 June (Reel AV 1338)
      Family scenes at cabin; horseback riding with family
      IV 3A7 Fa 4
    - Cascade Canyon, 1940 (Reel AV 1339)
      Fishing on lake; moose in the forest; panorama views from cabin.
      IV 3A7 Fa 5
    - Jackson Hole Summer 1939, 1939 Summer (Reel AV 1340)
      Fishing on lake; views of forest, geese, mountains
      IV 3A7 Fa 6
    - Geese on Phelps Lake, 1938 (Reel AV 1341)
      Horseback riding with family; train arriving; children playing at lake.
      IV 3A7 Fa 7
    - Jackson Hole 1938 (Reel AV 1342)
      Idaho Falls airport
      IV 3A7 Fa 8
    - Jackson Hole 1939 (Reel AV 1343)
      Windmill; driving on highway; very dark footage of some nighttime gathering
      IV 3A7 Fa 9
    - Harold P. Fabian films (Dvd AV 1326 - AV 1343)
      DVD access copy of Harold P. Fabian films AV 1326 - AV 1343.
  - Slides I - Puerto Rico, Dorado Beach, Virgin Islands, 1960-1964 (Box 68, Folder 616)
    Scenic views, friends, vacation activities.
    40 slides
  - Slides II - Virgin Islands, Little Dix Bay, 1960-1964 (Box 68, Folder 617)
  - Slides III - Little Dix Bay Fishing, San Jacinto, 1963-1964 (Box 68, Folder 618)
  - Miscellaneous Loose Slides (Box 68, Folder 619)